people-press.org 2019-04-02

# Privacy Policy | Pew Research Center

Effective Date:  March 27, 2018

Pew Research Center (“we,” “us,” or “our”) shares your concerns about maintaining the integrity and privacy of personal information collected on the internet.  We are committed to protecting your privacy, and this privacy policy (“Policy”) is intended to describe our information collection and dissemination practices in connection with Pew Research Center family of websites located at www.pewresearch.org or any website or service that links to or refers to this Policy (collectively, the “Sites”).

Please review the entire Policy and feel free to contact us using the contact information below if you have any questions.  By using the Sites, you consent to the collection, use, and disclosure of your information in accordance with the Policy.

**I.** **COLLECTION OF INFORMATION**

We may collect the following kinds of information when you use the Sites:

__Information you provide directly to us_._ For certain activities, such as when you register, subscribe to our alerts, download our datasets, or contact us directly, we may collect some or all of the following types of information:

Contact information, such as your full name, email address, mobile phone number, and address;

Username and password; and

Any other information you provide to us.

We may combine such information with information we may already have about you.

__Information we collect automatically_._ We may collect certain information automatically when you use our Sites, such as your Internet protocol (IP) address, device and advertising identifiers, browser type, operating system, Internet service provider, pages that you visit before and after using the Sites, the date and time of your visit, information about the links you click, the pages you view, the general manner in which you navigate the Sites, and other standard server log information.  We may also collect certain location information when you use our Sites, such as your computer’s IP address, your mobile device’s GPS signal, or information about nearby WiFi access points and cell towers.

We and third parties that provide content or functionality on our Sites, may use cookies, pixel tags, Local Shared Objects, and similar technologies to automatically collect this information.  For more information about cookies, pixel tags, Local Shared Objects, and similar technologies, please see the “Cookies” section below.

We may also collect technical data to address and fix technical problems and improve our Sites, including the memory state of your device when a system or app crash occurs while using our Sites.  Your device or browser settings may permit you to control the collection of this technical data.  This data may include parts of a document you were using when a problem occurred, or the contents of your communications.  By using the Sites, you are consenting to the collection of this technical data.

We may also receive information about you from other sources, including through third-party services and organizations.  For example, if you access third-party services, such as Facebook, Google, or Twitter, through the Sites to login to the Sites or to share information about your experience on the Sites with others, we may collect information from these third-party services.

**II.** **USE OF INFORMATION**

We generally use the information we collect online to:

  * Provide and improve the Sites;
  * Contact you, including for fundraising purposes;
  * Fulfill your requests for products, services, and information;
  * Send you promotional materials from us or on behalf of our affiliates and trusted third-party partners;
  * Analyze the use of the Sites and user data to understand and improve the Sites;
  * Customize the content you see when you use the Sites;
  * Prevent potentially prohibited or illegal activities and otherwise in accordance with our [Terms and Conditions](https://www.pewresearch.org/about/use-policy/terms-and-conditions/); and
  * For any other purposes disclosed to you at the time we collect your information or pursuant to your consent.

**III.** **SHARING OF INFORMATION**

We are committed to maintaining your trust, and we want you to understand when and with whom we may share the information we collect.

  * __Authorized third-party vendors and service providers_._ We may share your information with third-party vendors and service-providers that help us with specialized services, including billing, payment processing, customer service, email deployment, business analytics, marketing, advertising, performance monitoring, hosting, and data processing.
  * __Corporate affiliates__. We may share your information with our corporate affiliates that are subject to this policy.
  * __Business transfers_._ We may share your information in connection with a substantial corporate transaction, such as the sale of a website, a merger, consolidation, asset sale, or in the unlikely event of bankruptcy.
  * __Legal purposes_._ We may disclose information to respond to subpoenas, court orders, legal process, law enforcement requests, legal claims or government inquiries, and to protect and defend the rights, interests, health, safety, and security of Pew Research Center, our affiliates, users, or the public.
  * __With your consent or at your direction__. We may share information for any other purposes disclosed to you at the time we collect the information or pursuant to your consent or direction.

If you access third-party services, such as Facebook, Google, or Twitter, through the Sites to login to the Sites or to share information about your experience on the Sites with others, these third-party services may be able to collect information about you, including information about your activity on the Sites, and they may notify your connections on the third-party services about your use of the Sites, in accordance with their own privacy policies.

If you choose to engage in public activities on the Sites, you should be aware that any information you share there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these areas.  You should use caution in disclosing personal information while participating in these areas. We are not responsible for the information you choose to submit in these public areas.

**IV.** **SECURITY**

We use reasonable measures to help protect information from loss, theft, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction.  You should understand that no data storage system or transmission of data over the Internet or any other public network can be guaranteed to be 100 percent secure.  Please note that information collected by third parties may not have the same security protections as information you submit to us, and we are not responsible for protecting the security of such information.

**V.** **YOUR CHOICES**

You may opt out of our email newsletters by clicking the “unsubscribe” at the bottom of each newsletter and following the subsequent instructions.  You may also opt out of all communications from Pew Research Center by contacting us using the contact information below.

You may be able to refuse or disable cookies by adjusting your web browser settings.  Because each web browser is different, please consult the instructions provided by your web browser (typically in the “help” section).  Please note that you may need to take additional steps to refuse or disable Local Shared Objects and similar technologies.  For example, Local Shared Objects can be controlled through the instructions on Adobe’s [Setting Manager page](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html).  If you choose to refuse, disable, or delete these technologies, some of the functionality of the Sites may no longer be available to you.

California residents are entitled once a year, free of charge, to request and obtain certain information regarding our disclosure, if any, of certain categories of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year. We do not share personal information with third parties for their own direct marketing purposes.

**VI.** **THIRD-PARTY ADVERTISING, LINKS, AND CONTENT**

Some of the Sites may contain links to content maintained by third parties that we do not control.  We allow third parties, including business partners, advertising networks, and other advertising service providers, to collect information about your online activities through cookies, pixels, local storage, and other technologies. These third parties may use this information to display advertisements on our Sites and elsewhere online tailored to your interests, preferences, and characteristics.  We are not responsible for the privacy practices of these third parties, and the information practices of these third parties are not covered by this Privacy Policy.

Some third parties collect information about users of our Sites to provide interest-based advertising on our Sites and elsewhere, including across browsers and devices.  These third parties may use the information they collect on our Sites to make predictions about your interests in order to provide you ads (from us and other companies) across the internet.  Some of these third parties may participate in an industry organization that gives users the opportunity to opt out of receiving ads that are tailored based on your online activities.  Due to differences between using apps and websites on mobile devices, you may need to take additional steps to disable targeted ad technologies in mobile apps.  Many mobile devices allow you to opt out of targeted advertising for mobile apps using the settings within the mobile app or your mobile device.  For more information, please check your mobile settings.  You also may uninstall our apps using the standard uninstall process available on your mobile device or app marketplace.

To opt out of interest-based advertising across browsers and devices from companies that participate in the [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.aboutads.info/) or [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) opt-out programs, please visit their respective websites.  You may also be able to opt out of interest-based advertising through the settings within the mobile app or your mobile device, but your opt-out choice may apply only to the browser or device you are using when you opt out, so you should opt out on each of your browsers and devices if you want to disable all cross-device linking for interest-based advertising.  If you opt out, you will still receive ads but they may not be as relevant to you and your interests, and your experience on our Sites may be degraded.

__Do-Not-Track Signals and Similar Mechanisms__. Some web browsers transmit “do-not-track” signals to websites. Because of differences in how web browsers incorporate and activate this feature, it is not always clear whether users intend for these signals to be transmitted, or whether they even are aware of them. We currently do not take action in response to these signals.

**VII. COOKIES**

Cookies are small bits of information that are stored by your computer’s web browser.  Pixel tags are very small images or small pieces of data embedded in images, also known as “web beacons” or “clear GIFs,” that can recognize cookies, the time and date a page is viewed, a description of the page where the pixel tag is placed, and similar information from your computer or device.  Local Shared Objects (sometimes referred to as “Flash Cookies”) are similar to standard cookies except that they can be larger and are downloaded to a computer or mobile device by the Adobe Flash media player.  To find out more above cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and delete them, visit www.aboutcookies.org or www.allaboutcookies.org.

We use cookies, Local Shared Objects, and similar technologies for technical reasons to enable the efficient operation of the Sites, to enhance the ease of use of the Sites, and to gather statistics on how you use our Sites.  By using the Sites, you consent to our use of cookies and similar technologies.  You may opt out of cookies and similar technologies in accordance with the “Choices” section above, but please understand that certain functionalities on the Site may no longer function for you if you choose to do so.

**VIII.** **INTERNATIONAL USERS**

We maintain information in the United States of America and in accordance with the laws of the United States, which may not provide the same level of protection as the laws in your jurisdiction.  By using the Sites and providing us with information, you understand and agree that your information may be transferred to and stored on servers located outside your resident jurisdiction and, to the extent you are a resident of a country other than the United States, that you consent to the transfer of such data to the United States for processing by us in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

**XI.** **CHILDREN**

We do not knowingly collect any personal information from children under the age of 13 without parental consent, unless permitted by law.  If we learn that a child under the age of 13 has provided us with personal information, we will delete it in accordance with applicable law.

**X.** **CHANGES TO THE PRIVACY POLICY**

We may update this Policy from time to time. When we update the Policy, we will revise the “Effective Date” date above and post the new Privacy Policy.  We recommend that you review the Privacy Policy each time you visit the Sites to stay informed of our privacy practices.

**XI.** **CONTACT INFORMATION**

If you have any questions about this Policy or our practices, please contact us at:

Pew Research Center  
1615 L St. NW  
Suite 800  
Washington, D.C. 20036

Telephone: (+1) 202-419-4300  
Email: [info@pewresearch.org](mailto:info@pewresearch.org)
